<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on So what ...</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on So what ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Gilles Kratzer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So what ... </title>
      <link>/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>just another blog about statistics and data analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I like to call myself data engineer. It is a way for me to mix my engineer degree in Physics with my degree in Biostatistics. I like to take a problem and to bring a practical solution. I like the machine learning approaches which I found very powerful and have high potential for solving practical challenges in data analysis. But I try to not forget that this is in fact re-branding of statistics methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recents Posts</title>
      <link>/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/home/soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/soft/</guid>
      <description> author of varrank R package that perform variable selection with applications in systemic datasets  maintainer of abn R package that models multivariate data with Additive Bayesian Networks  contributor of ATR R package for plotting party trees in left-right orientation instead of the classical top-down layout   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks/Posters</title>
      <link>/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/talks/</guid>
      <description>Futur events:
 2-3 July 2018, BAYSM 2018, Warwick. Poster: Comparison between Suitable Priors for Additive Bayesian Networks.  Past events:
 21-23 March 2018. Society for Veterinary Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine (SVEPM), Tallinn. Poster: Information-Theoretic Scoring Rules to Learn Additive Bayesian Network Applied to Epidemiology. 24-26 July 2017. TIES GRASPA, Bergamo. Poster: Additive Bayesian Network approach applied to time series and longitudinal datasets.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>