<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on </title>
    <link>/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Gilles Kratzer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>mcmcabn</title>
      <link>/project/mcmcabn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mcmcabn/</guid>
      <description>Flexible implementation of a structural MCMC sampler for Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs). It supports the new edge reversal move from Grzegorczyk and Husmeier (2008) doi:10.1007/s10994-008-5057-7 and the Markov blanket resampling from Su and Borsuk (2016) http://jmlr.org/papers/v17/su16a.html. It supports three priors: a prior controlling for structure complexity from Koivisto and Sood (2004) http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1005332.1005352, an uninformative prior and a user-defined prior. The three main problems that can be addressed by this R package are selecting the most probable structure based on a cache of pre-computed scores, controlling for overfitting, and sampling the landscape of high scoring structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>abn</title>
      <link>/project/abn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/abn/</guid>
      <description>The study of the causes and effect of health and disease condition is a cornerstone of the epidemiology. Classical approaches, such as regression techniques have been successfully used to model the impact of health determinants over the whole population. However, recently there is a growing recognition of biological, behavioural factors, at multiple levels that can impact the health condition. These epidemiological data are, by nature, highly complex and correlated. Classical regression framework have shown limited abilities to embrace the correlated multivariate nature of high dimensional epidemiological variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>varrank</title>
      <link>/project/varrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/varrank/</guid>
      <description>A common challenge encountered when working with high dimensional datasets is that of variable selection. All relevant confounders must be taken into account to allow for unbiased estimation of model parameters, while balancing with the need for parsimony and producing interpretable models. This task is known to be one of the most controversial and difficult tasks in epidemiological analysis.
Variable selection approaches can be categorized into three broad classes: filter-based methods, wrapper-based methods, and embedded methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>