<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on So what ...</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on So what ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Gilles Kratzer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A battle to the death</title>
      <link>/post/pval/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pval/</guid>
      <description>It is unanimously agreed that statistics depends somehow on probability. But, as to what probability is and how it is connected with statistics, there has seldom been such complete disagreement and breakdown of communication since the Tower of Babel. Savage, The Foundations of Statistics (1972)
Recentely, I had to give a presentation about P value and I discovered during the preparation of this talk a battle to the death within statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility in Science</title>
      <link>/post/natruecommunication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/natruecommunication/</guid>
      <description>As a biostatistician I am particularly concerned by reproducibility in research (RR). I try very hard to do reproducible research. It is often hard. Often this is not clear how to achieve RR. Within our group, we had recently some discussions about RR. Below is a small personal manifesto for RR.
Manifesto for reproducible research I believe that good science is made of trustable science. I believe that the most trustable academic research can only be achieved with a rigorous application of scientific methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility in Science</title>
      <link>/post/repro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/repro/</guid>
      <description>As a biostatistician I am particularly concerned by reproducibility in research (RR). I try very hard to do reproducible research. It is often hard. Often this is not clear how to achieve RR. Within our group, we had recently some discussions about RR. Below is a small personal manifesto for RR.
Manifesto for reproducible research I believe that good science is made of trustable science. I believe that the most trustable academic research can only be achieved with a rigorous application of scientific methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Ngram</title>
      <link>/post/ngram/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ngram/</guid>
      <description>The Google Ngram Viewer, started in December 2010, is an online search engine that returns the yearly relative frequency of a set of words, found in a selected printed sources, called corpus of books, between 1500 and 2016 (many language available). More specifically, it returns the relative frequency of the yearly ngram (continuous set of n words. For example, I is a 1-gram and I am is a 2-grams). This means that if you search for one word (called unigram), you get the percentage of this word to all the other word found in the corpus of books for a certain year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>